ELIAS SPECTOR-ZABUSKY

607-592-5831 | elias.spector.zabusky@gmail.com | Brooklyn, New York

inkedin.com/in/elias-sz | O eithub.com/ColdWeatherBoyy | www.EliasSZ.com/

SUMMARY

Web developer, digital native, and musician working with the MERN stack, with an interest in backend development, product work, databases, and AI. Graduate of Columbia's Coding Bootcamp with experience in project management, operations, and the arts. Strong skills in creative problem-solving and collaboration, partnered with a focus on flexibility, meticulousness, and camaraderie. Analytically minded with a knack for aiding decision-making.

PROJECTS

FRAiME | github.com/ColinSprows/Fraime | http://www.FRAiMED.art/

Co-Founder and Lead Developer. FRAiME is an eCommerce platform still in development, leveraging OpenAI's DALL-E API to allow users to generate bespoke art and order high-quality prints. Future features include selectable preprompts, finetuning options, and print ordering. MERN stack, Next.js, Styled Components.

- Co-planned the backend architecture and data flow; coded majority of CRUD routes and database models.
- Collaborated on the design of the user interface, with a focus on customer experience and ease of use.

Dada Art Museum | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/dada-museum | dada-museum.herokuapp.com

Lead Developer and UI Designer. Proof of concept showcase project. Co-designed and implemented UI for a museum's homepage with a focus on functional and engaging features. Node.js, React, Express, Chakra UI.

- Coded Current Exhibits and Featured Artist sections; built reusable components for consistent site UX.
- Implemented random art feature, using on click and on page load calls to the Art Institute of Chicago's API.

Vite React Template | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyv/vite-template | template-test-1.herokuapp.com

Lead Engineer. A template for MERN applications, with basic authorization capabilities baked in using JSON Web Token and a connection to a MongoDB preconfigured. Basic routes and IWT testable with an app like Insomnia. MERN stack, React Router, DotEnv, Bcrypt, and JSON Web Token.

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Jan. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL ONLINE

Feb. 2023 - Apr. 2023

Certificate in Business Analytics

Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island

Bachelor of Arts in Theatre Arts and Performance Studies

Phi Beta Kappa; T. Carpenter Elocution Award

2011 - 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, GraphQL, NoSQL

Frontend: React, Chakra UI, Next.is, Styled Components, Handlebars, Vite

Backend: MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL

Development Tools: VS Code, Figma, Insomnia, Chrome Dev Tools, Git, GitHub

Other: MS Excel, Google Analytics, Shopify, Chat GPT prompting

EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL MUSICIAN

Nov. 2015 – Present

Band-member, producer, songwriter, and/or arranger for a few NYC-based bands. www.stolenjars.com

DIGITAL CONTENT AND MERCHANDISE MANAGER

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2023

ROBIN BARON DESIGN; NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Led product-related operations for an interior designer's eCommerce business and acted as admin of the Shopify site. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop strategic plans for growth.

- Maintained and revised HTML and CSS for site content as needed; added custom in-line CSS for blog features.
- Spearheaded the product upload for site launch, bringing the project up to speed in 6 weeks. In line with growth roadmap, managed a team of 8-10 freelancers in the upload of 12,500+ SKUs from ~40 vendors.

INDEPENDENT EDITOR AND CONSULTANT, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2023

Offered editorial and writing services for resumes and cover letters, helping earn multiple clients' new jobs.